Strings Reloads - SRL 
Created By Marcussacana

--How to, Strings.lst
Translate strings in the Strings.lst with the Notepad++,
For every line you can see 2 copies, the first is requeried you can't edit it!
translate the second copy of a line and launch the game by the Evangile.exe,
after launch you see a loading window, after the open the main menu, close it.
now you can found a "Strings.srl" in the directory, you need share the MyGame.exe, SRLx32.dll and Strings.srl

--How to reload the string by byte comparsion
In the Strings.lst put your string started as 0x and all bytes in hex, by sample 0x48656C6C6F to "Hello"
Some times the game can have special chars that miss the string when decoded, and with this feature
you can reload the by byte match.
If you want dump/see a string Bytes, run the game with the paramter -log

--How to, Chars.lst
This file is the list of fake characters to inject in the game while running...
Sample: á=*
That indicate every string in the Strings.srl is replaced 'á' with the '*' when the game request the translation,
And when he try render the '*' he replace with the 'á', this is a custom list because you can't put the * char in your translation, why? 
why is now reserved to the String Reloader

--The á=* show the */not show the char... what i do?
Launch the game with the paramter -debug and open the dialog with the problem
In the debug ouput you can see a message "Missed Char", search for a corruped char, something like this:
l=?|n=0xFFAB (search for this 0xFF??)
You need know what is the correct char to render that miss...
in the case 'á', now append this line in the Chars.lst as sample:
á=0xFFAB
Delete the "Strings.srl" and open the game and try again.


--Command Line Options
launch the  game with -help to see the command line options.

--WordWrap
This allow do a custom Auto-WordWrap to your game, you can setup at the SRL.ini the WordWrap
Bold, FontSize and FontName I don't need explain.
The MaxWidth is the "Max Length" of a string.
if monospaced is false, this MaxWidth is pixels, else is max char count per line.
You can set a custom Width to a specified line, just place at the begin of the translation:
::MaxWidth[??]:: (where ?? is the MaxWidth value), if you wanna disable the wordwrap to a line just place at the begin of the line: ::NOWORDWRAP::

--Mask Mactch
This allow translate strings with a unpredictable part.
To use this feature just place {0},{1},{2},{3}... 
in the match line, by sample:
You have gained {0} x{1}
Wow, you gained the item {0} (x{1})
Now if the game give the string: 
You have gained HP Potion x30
You will recive as result: 
Wow, you gained the item HP Potion (x30)
And if you need reload a string that the content inside {} isn't a match mask, put ::NOMASK:: at the begin of the translation line, by sample:
Mother: {Hey, Wake up!}
::NOMASK::Mother: {WAKE UP YOUR NIGGA!!}
This will return: Mother: {WAKE UP YOUR NIGGA!!}


--Overlay Events Triggers
You can put events with the reloaded text that trigger a event to the overlay
To trigger a event the reloaded text needs starts with "::EVENT?::" (? = Event ID)
Keep in mind the ID 0 can't be used since he is a 'intialize' event automatically triggered at the overlay initialization

--Overlay Event Scripting
This is a small scripting format that I created, The better formating to this script that I found, is the YAML
The comment prefix is "#"
The prefix ":" means a event begin, after the prefix you need give the event id (needs be a number)
All "Actions" that needs pass a value needs : after the action name, example: Dock: Bottom
Example:

#This is a Comment

#Begin the Event with id 1
:1
#End the Event 1
End Event

Okay, Now you see the scpt "struct" I will explain the commands
:?? (Create a Event with the ?? ID) 
End Event (Finish the 'atual' event)
Call: ?? (Call a event with ID ??)
Jump: ?? (Jump to a event with ID ??)
Dock: Bottom/Center/Top (Dock the overlay at the bottom, top or center of the game window)
Show Text: Text (Show 'Text' in the Overlay, use \n to break the line)
Clear (Clear the Overlay Text)
Hide Overlay (Hide the overlay window)
Show Overlay (Show the overlay window)
Opacity: 0,9 (Set the overlay window opacity, a value from 0,0 at 1,0)
Back Color: Black (Change the overlay background color, Example: Black/#000/#000000/0; 0; 0)
Text Color: White (Change the overlay text color, see the Back color example)
Padding: Top: 15%|Bottom: -45%|Left: 0|Rigth: 0 (Set the Overlay Window Padding, can have negative values and percentages)
Font Size: 14,6 (Set the Overlay Font Size)
Auto Font Size: true/false (When true the overlay font size will be allways the max size to show all text without lost)
Hook (Make the overlay show all string reloads text)